rogers.com 2004-12-11

# Rogers.com | Privacy Policy

Rogers Communications Inc. develops and operates the rogers.com Web site. 

Frequently Asked Questions   
  
---  
  
  * What is personal information?
  * Does Rogers Communications Inc. ask for personal information?
  * How does Rogers Communications Inc. use information it gathers about me?
  * Does Rogers Communications Inc. share my personal information? If so, with whom?
  * When else might Rogers Communications Inc. use my personal information?
  * Will my information be used by Rogers Communications Inc. for direct mailings?
  * How does Rogers Communications Inc. protect the privacy of children?
  * Does www.rogers.com use cookies?
  * How can I disable cookies?
  * Does Rogers Communications Inc. use the Internet provider addresses?
  * What else should I know about my privacy?

Rogers Communications Inc. Privacy Policy  
  
  * Rogers Communications Inc. Privacy Policy

What is personal information?|   

Personal information may include such information as your name, email address, mailing addresses, financial information, birth dates and information collected electronically via cookies.  

Does Rogers Communications Inc. ask for personal information?

|   

Possibly. Rogers Communications Inc. will ask for your name, address, email address (mandatory), and other personal information when you register with rogers.com. You will also be asked for personal information when you make a purchase from the site, or enter into contests or promotions sponsored by us or sponsored by our partners.  

How does Rogers Communications Inc. use information it gathers about me?

|   

Rogers Communications Inc. collects and uses your name, email address and other personal information, for example, to provide you with a product or service that you requested. This information also enables Rogers Communications Inc. to develop and customize products or services to better meet your needs and preferences and to offer you products and services from Rogers Communications Inc., any of its affiliated companies within the Rogers group of companies, and other sources that may be of interest to you.  

Does Rogers Communications Inc. share my personal information? If so, with whom?

|   

Rogers Communications Inc. will not release your personal information with these exceptions: 

  * When you give us permission to do so;
  * When we believe in good faith that the law requires it;
  * To protect the rights or property of Rogers Communications Inc. or its affiliates;
  * Under limited circumstances specifically described to you when we collect the information, such as in a Terms of Service or Use agreement, or in the rules of sweepstakes or other promotions;
  * To affiliated companies within the Rogers group of companies.

When else might Rogers Communications Inc. use my personal information?

|   

Subject to confidentiality agreements, Rogers Communications Inc. may match aggregated, statistical user information to parameters established by third parties, without releasing user information. This aggregated information does not contain any personally identifiable information. For example, we may disclose aggregated user statistics (for example, 31% of our users are professionals) in order to describe our site or services to trading partners, advertisers, other third parties and for other lawful purposes.  

Will Rogers Communications Inc. use my information for direct mailings?

|   

Rogers Communications Inc. or Rogers affiliated companies may send you information about our products or services that may be of interest to you. If you do not want to receive direct mailings, all you have to do is say so when you give us your personal information. If you have given permission and change your mind, you can ask to be taken out of future direct mailings.  

How does Rogers Communications Inc. protect the privacy of children?

|   

The privacy of children is important to us. Your children should always ask you for permission before sending personal information to Rogers Communications Inc., or to anyone else. Any personal information we gather from children under the age of 16 would be used solely for demographic purposes. We will not knowingly send direct mailings, including email or other correspondence to anyone who indicates that they are younger than 16 years.  

Does [www.rogers.com](http://www.rogers.com/) use cookies?

|   

Yes, [www.rogers.com](http://www.rogers.com/) uses cookies. A cookie is set when you register on our site. Cookies are required to: 

  * View and pay your bills online 
  * Perform self service activities on the site. 
  * Determine which browser you are using so we can ensure the site is designed to work properly with the most common versions of different browsers. 

When you register with us your browser must be set to accept cookies. A cookie is a text record placed on our hard drive that tells us who you are so that the site can remember information you have given us in the past, or activities you have carried out on our site. The cookies can only contain data you've told us about yourself. They cannot examine your computer or read data from it. If you are worried about the information we place in the cookie, you may delete the file(s) at the end of each browser session. Your browser's help file will have instructions on how to do that. If you are interested in learning more about how cookies work, you can visit [http://www.cookiecentral.com](http://www.cookiecentral.com/)  

How can I disable cookies?

|   

Both Netscape and Microsoft Internet Explorer (MSIE) allow some level of cookie verification or choice. Netscape 3.0 and MSIE 3.0 allow you only an "alert before accepting cookies." This way you can voluntarily choose not to visit a site or areas of a site that use cookies.

To be alerted about accepting cookies, please follow one of these procedures (the following is only a brief list of some popular browsers):

If you are using Netscape Navigator 3.0, go to the "Options" menu, then to "Network Preferences," and then to "Protocols." Check the box that says, "Show an alert before accepting a cookie." 

In Netscape 4.0+, go to "Edit" in the menu bar, then to "Preferences," then to "Advanced." Check the box that says, "Warn me before accepting a cookie." 

In Netscape 6.0, go to "Edit" in the menu bar, then to "Preferences," then to "Advanced," then to "Cookies." Check the box that says, "Warn me before accepting a cookie." 

In Internet Explorer 3.0, go to the "View" menu, then to "Options," then to "Advanced." Check the box that says, "Warn before accepting cookies." 

In Internet Explorer 4.0, go to the "View" menu, then to "Internet Options," then to "Advanced." Check the box that says, "Prompt before accepting cookies." 

In Internet Explorer 5.0, go to the "Tools" menu, then to "Internet Options," then to "Security," then to "Custom Level." In the "Cookies" section, go to the "Allow cookies that are stored on your machine" sub-section and select "Prompt."   

Does Rogers Communications Inc. use IP addresses?

|   

Rogers Communications Inc. collects IP addresses for the purposes of system administration and to create aggregate statistical reports for advertisers.   

What else should I know about protecting my privacy?

|   

Generally speaking, whenever you disclose personal information online, that information may be intercepted, collected and used. That goes for information disclosed on message boards, in chat areas - or even in email. If you post personal information online, that information may be intercepted and may be accessible to the public and may expose you to unsolicited messages. Rogers Communications Inc. is not responsible if that information is intercepted. As a result, you transmit information to anyone at your own risk. 

Rogers Communications Inc.’s partners, co-branded sites and third party Internet sites and services accessible through our site, or third parties collecting information for their own contests or promotions may have their own privacy and data collection practices. Rogers Communications Inc. is not responsible for and bears no liability for these policies or actions. 

You alone are responsible for keeping passwords and information safe. Be careful and responsible whenever you’re online.   

Rogers Communications Inc. Privacy Policy

|   
  
Rogers Communications Inc. has created this Privacy Policy in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this Web site: www.rogers.com 

We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our Web site. Your IP address is also used to gather broad demographic information. Our site may use cookies to make sure you don’t see the same ad repeatedly. We use cookies to deliver content specific to your interests, to save your password so you don’t have to re-enter it each time you visit our site, and for the other purposes set out below: 

  * We use cookies to remind us who you are and to find your account information in our database when you access a service so you do not need to log in at every visit. This helps us to provide you with service tailored to your specific needs and interests. A cookie is set when you register for a service.
  * We use cookies to estimate our audience size. Your browser is given a unique cookie that helps us determine whether yours is a repeat visit or a first visit.
  * We use cookies to determine the browser the visitor uses so the site can be designed to work properly with the most common versions of different browsers.
  * Advertisers that place ads with Rogers Communications Inc. may use cookies

Our site’s registration forms require users to give us a unique username and password. To post a message in Rogers Communications Inc. using an e-form, an email address is also required. 

This site contains links to third party sites. Rogers Communications Inc. or any of its affiliates is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. Rogers Communications Inc. co-branded sites and content partner sites may have privacy policies independent of Rogers Communications Inc. This Privacy Policy extends only to data collected on pages hosted on the Rogers Communications Inc. servers. Rogers Communications Inc. may share aggregate information with trading partners, co-branded sites, and advertisers, however, this aggregated information does not contain personally identifiable information. 

Our online surveys may ask visitors for such information as contact information (like their email address), financial information (like their investment portfolio holdings), and demographic information (like their postal code, age or income level). We may use contact data from our surveys to send information about our company and promotional material from some of our partners or advertisers. The customer’s contact information may also be used to contact the visitor when necessary and may be shared with other affiliated companies within the Rogers group of companies who may want to contact our visitors. Only Rogers Communications Inc. or affiliated companies within the Rogers group of companies have access to your personal information. Users may opt-out of receiving future e-mail communications. Please see the choice/opt-out section below. 

Demographic and profile data is also collected at our site. We use this data to tailor our visitor’s experience at our site and display the content according to their preferences. This information is shared with advertisers on an aggregate basis only. 

We run contests on our site in which we ask visitors for contact information (like their email address), financial information (like investment portfolio holdings), and demographic information (like their postal code, age, or income level). We may use contact data from our contests to send users information about our company, and promotional material from some of our partners. The customer’s contact information is also used to contact the visitor when necessary and may be shared with other companies or affiliated companies within the Rogers group of companies who may want to contact our visitors. Only Rogers Communications Inc. or affiliated companies within the Rogers group of companies have access to your personal information. Users may opt-out of receiving future e-mail communications; see the choice/opt-out section below.   

How does rogers.com handle disputes regarding their privacy policy?

|   

Whereas this web site shall be bound by the standards as set out by the W3C, and reserves the right to determine what constitutes a privacy breach. Any disagreement a user might have with the privacy policy may contact customer service at 1-877-343-5745.   

Public Forums

|   

This site makes chat rooms, forums, message boards and/or news groups available to its users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information.  

Security

|   

This site has reasonable security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse and be intercepted by third parties. Rogers Communications Inc. or any of its affiliated companies within the Rogers group of companies assumes no liability for interception, alteration or misuse of information transmitted over the Internet.  

Children’s Guidelines

|   

Rogers Communications Inc. is not marketed or directed towards children. Nevertheless, it is possible for children to publicly post or distribute personally identifiable contact information without prior parental consent within chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or news groups. No communication, however, will be sent to anyone or information collected from anyone who indicates that they are younger than 16 years old without their parents’ permission.  

Choice/Opt-Out

|   

In the Registration process where we request information about the visitor, our site provides users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving email or other forms of communications from us, our affiliated companies and our trading partners.  

Contacting Us

|   

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact: 

Ken Engelhart  
Rogers Communications Inc.  
333 Bloor Street East  
Toronto, Ontario  
M4W 1G9
